https://globalmarch.org/privacy-policy/

Last Updated: 27 July 2020
Global March Against Child about (Global March) processes personal data and other data in compliance with the applicable laws. We feel very strongly about privacy, and handle personal data with all due care.
You can contact us at info@globalmarch.org to access or modify your data whenever you wish. You can use the same email address to inform us if you no longer wish to receive updates about our work.
Read on to find out how we handle personal data.
Scope of applicability
The present privacy policy applies to all processing operations concerning personal information supplied by donors and relations (hereinafter: ‘Personal Data’) and data acquired from individuals’ visits to and use of Global March’s websites.
By participating in one of our campaigns or becoming a donor, supporter or partner, you accept this privacy policy and give your consent to Global March to collect and store your data and process them in the manners described in the present policy.
Data processing
Global March Against Child Labour processes Personal Data for its supporter and donor records, for its awareness raising and fundraising programmes and for providing information about our work and campaigns.
Global March ensures that the systems in which Personal Data are stored have appropriate organisational and technical security. This serves to ensure that Personal Data is accessible only by employees whose jobs carry the necessary authorisation and that we use the Personal Data only for the purposes for which they were acquired and for compatible purposes. In so far as Global March Against Child Labour engages service providers to assist with recordkeeping, fundraising or providing information, the use of the data and the security measures implemented by those parties are recorded in data processing agreements.
Your data will not be disclosed to other third parties without your explicit consent, except where it is required by law to disclose those data.
In connection with tax laws, the retention period for our donor records is 7 years. Data from newsletter subscribers are removed as soon as the individual unsubscribes.
Data collected through the Internet
Global March Against Child Labour collects Personal Data through its websites. This happens when a visitor subscribes to one of our email newsletters, participates in an online campaign or signs up as a donor.
Data collected through sources other than the Internet
Global March Against Child Labour also collects your Personal Data if you take part in a Global March campaign, or if you are recruited as a donor, using an application form, email request or by any other means.
Email
If you have supplied Global March Against Child Labour with your email address as a newsletter subscriber, a donor or an information recipient, you will receive emails informing you about our work and asking you to support our campaigns.
When Global March sends out electronic mailings, we use a system that provides information about the method used for opening the email. That system also offers the possibility of tracking whether readers click on the links in our emails. Global March does this to align the information provided to you more closely to your interests.
To withdraw your consent for receiving information by email, use the unsubscribe link in the appropriate email or else contact Global March by sending an email to info@globalmarch.org.
Communications with donors
If you subscribe as a donor, we will record the Personal Data that you provide in our donor records. Global March sends new donors an acknowledgment email to confirm the donation. Global March informs its donors of its work by email or social media.
Our donor records also contain Personal Data of relations. A relation is a person who is registered with Global March (for example having taken part in a campaign, subscribed to a newsletter or requested information) without being a donor.
Cookies
Global March Against Child Labour uses GDPR Cookie as per EU GDPR/Cookie Law regulations. Cookies are tiny text files that Internet pages store on a visitor’s PC, tablet or mobile telephone. Those cookies are used to improve the user-friendliness of Global March’s websites and to monitor visits to those websites.
You can disable or delete cookies whenever you wish. You can adjust the settings in your browser to notify you as soon as you receive a cookie, or else to disable cookies. However, this might interfere with the website’s optimum performance.
Google Analytics
Global March Against Child Labour uses Google Analytics to collect information about details such as the date and time of your visit to our website and the pages that you viewed. We use these data for improving its website, compiling traffic statistics (e.g. the times of day or the days of the week when the website receives the highest numbers of visitors) and for assessing the popularity of the various parts of the website. Global March only uses these data in aggregated form, and cannot trace them back to particular devices or individuals. You can install the Google Analytics Opt-out Browser Add-on to stop our website from forwarding information about your visits to Google Analytics.
Social networks
Our websites contain buttons and widgets for the Facebook, Twitter, YouTube and Instagram social networks, to make it easier for you to share Global March campaigns and Global March news with friends. Those social networks are connected to web servers that can trace your activity on our website and combine the results with other information from other websites. Social media cookies are only stored if you are logged in to the relevant media while visiting the Global March website and if you give permission. You can disable this function by installing a program such as Disconnect for Chrome and Firefox.
Security
Global March Against Child Labour has implemented appropriate technical and organisational measures to secure Personal Data against loss or any form of unlawful processing. Our donor page uses Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) to ensure that payment details remain secure. SSL is a protocol that ensures that Internet communications remain secure and that is designed to prevent eavesdropping, interference and message falsification. If you are on a secure page such as our donor form, your browser should inform you that you are on a secure site.
Global March uses SSL to secure sensitive information, and also secures offline user information. Access to all your data is restricted. Only employees who need that information to carry out specific tasks can access those Personal Data.
Questions
If you have any questions about how Global March processes your Personal Data, and what Personal Data is processed, please contact us at info@globalmarch.org. Global March may ask you for proof of identity before we may grant you access to your Personal Data in our records.
Global March reserves the right to update its privacy policy. We recommend that you check this privacy policy regularly for any changes.
+91 11 49211111
info@globalmarch.org
Global March Against Child LabourAbout Us
Contact Us
Blog
Regional Representatives
Global MarchPrivacy
Terms
Sitemap
BECOME A VOLUNTEER
Join your hand with us for a better life and beautiful future
Join Us Now
Thank you for visiting our website!
Globalmarch.org uses cookies to enhance your user experience. More information is available in our privacy and cookie statement.
ACCEPTPrivacy & Cookies Policy
Close
Privacy Overview
This website uses cookies to improve your experience while you navigate through the website. Out of these cookies, the cookies that are categorized as necessary are stored on your browser as they are essential for the working of basic functionalities of the website. We also use third-party cookies that help us analyze and understand how you use this website. These cookies will be stored in your browser only with your consent. You also have the option to opt-out of these cookies. But opting out of some of these cookies may have an effect on your browsing experience.
Necessary
Always Enabled
Necessary cookies are absolutely essential for the website to function properly. This category only includes cookies that ensures basic functionalities and security features of the website. These cookies do not store any personal information.
Non-necessary
Non-necessary
Any cookies that may not be particularly necessary for the website to function and is used specifically to collect user personal data via analytics, ads, other embedded contents are termed as non-necessary cookies. It is mandatory to procure user consent prior to running these cookies on your website.
Translate »
